singerco.com 2019-10-15

# Privacy and Security Policies | Singer.com

### Safe Shopping Promise

Be assured that all transactions conducted online with Singer Sewing Company are completely secure and confidential. Our high encryption standards guarantee that any credit card purchase is conducted safely and without risk. We stand behind our security system with complete confidence - in the unlikely event that an unauthorized payment is charged to a customer account, Singer Sewing Company promises to cover the cost. However, if it makes you more comfortable, you can submit your order and conduct the credit card transaction by phone at this number: 1-800-4-SINGER.

### Privacy Policy

This SVP WORLDWIDE Privacy Policy was updated on February 21, 2019. Your privacy is important to SVP Worldwide so we’ve developed a Privacy Policy that covers how we collect, use, disclose, transfer, and store your personal information.

Please take a moment to familiarize yourself with our privacy practices and [contact us](mailto:privacy@svpworldwide.com?subject=Privacy%20Inquiry%20V052518) if you have any questions.

#### Collection and Use of Personal Information

Personal information is data that can be used to identify or contact a single person. You may be asked to provide your personal information anytime you are in contact with SVP Worldwide or an affiliated company. SVP Worldwide and its affiliates may share this personal information with each other and use it consistent with this Privacy Policy. They may also combine it with other information to provide and improve our products, services, content, and advertising. You are not required to provide the personal information that we have requested, but, if you chose not to do so, in many cases we will not be able to provide you with our products or services or respond to any queries you may have.

Here are some examples of the types of personal information SVP Worldwide may collect and how we may use it:

**What personal information we collect**

We collect personal information when you:

  * Create a mySewnet™ account,
  * Purchase a product from SINGER®, HUSQVARNA VIKING®, or PFAFF®,
  * Download software or an update from PREMIER+™,
  * Subscribe to a newsletter on one of our websites or via social media,
  * Register for a class at a Viking Sewing Gallery Retail Store,
  * Connect to our services,
  * Register your machine’s warranty,
  * Submit a rebate form,
  * Contact us,
  * And/or participate in an online survey

The categories of personal information we collect may include your:  

  * Name,
  * Mailing address,
  * Phone number,
  * Email address,
  * Birth date,
  * Purchase history,
  * Contact preferences,
  * Device identifiers,
  * IP address, and/or
  * Credit card information.

**How we use your personal  information**

We may process your personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy with your consent or when we have assessed it is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by SVP Worldwide or a third party to whom it may be necessary to disclose information.

  * The personal information we collect allows us to keep you posted on SVP Worldwide’s latest sales and promotions, product announcements, software updates, and upcoming events. If you don’t want to be on our mailing list, you can opt out anytime by clicking “Unsubscribe” at the bottom of any communication.
  * We also use personal information to help us create, develop, operate, deliver, and improve our products, services, content, and advertising
  * We may use your personal information, including date of birth to determine appropriate services. For example, the mySewnet™ site is not intended for users under the age of 16.
  * From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about purchases and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies. Because this information is important to your interaction with SVP Worldwide, you may not opt out of receiving these communications.
  * We may also use personal information for internal purposes such as auditing, data analysis, and research to improve SVP Worldwide’s products, services, and customer communications.
  * If you enter into a sweepstake, contest, or similar promotion we may use the information you provide to administer those programs.

#### Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information

We also collect data in a form that does not, on its own, permit direct association with any specific individual. We may collect, use, transfer, and disclose non-personal information for any purpose. The following are some examples of non-personal information that we collect and how we may use it:

  * We may collect information such as language, zip code, area code, unique device identifier, and referrer URL so that we can better understand customer behavior and improve our products, services, and advertising.
  * We may collect information regarding customer activities on our website and from our other products and services. This information is aggregated and used to help us provide more useful information to our customers and to understand which parts of our website, products, and services are of most interest. Aggregated data is considered non‑personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.
  * We may collect and store details of how you use our services, including search queries. This information may be used to improve the relevancy of results provided by our services. Except in limited instances to ensure quality of our services over the Internet, such information will not be associated with your IP address.
  * With your explicit consent, we may collect data about how you use your device and applications in order to help our app developers improve our apps.

If we do combine non-personal information with personal information the combined information will be treated as personal information for as long as it remains combined.

#### Cookies and Other Technologies

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. 

These technologies help us better understand user behavior, tell us which parts of our websites people have visited, and facilitate and measure the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches. We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as non‑personal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

As is true of most Internet services, we gather some information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit websites and applications, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, to improve our product and services, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. SVP Worldwide may use this information in our marketing and advertising services.

Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Find out how to manage cookies on popular browsers:

  * Google Chrome
  * Microsoft Edge
  * Mozilla Firefox
  * Microsoft Internet Explorer
  * Opera
  * Apple Safari

To find information relating to other browsers, visit the browser developer's website. To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, visit [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

#### Disclosure to Third Parties

At times SVP Worldwide may make certain personal information available to strategic partners that work with SVP Worldwide to provide products and services, or that help SVP Worldwide market to customers. Personal information will only be shared by SVP Worldwide to provide or improve our products, services and advertising; it will not be shared with third parties for their marketing purposes.

#### Service Providers

SVP Worldwide shares personal information with companies who provide services such as information processing, extending credit, fulfilling customer orders, delivering products to you, managing and enhancing customer data, providing customer service, assessing your interest in our products and services, and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are obligated to protect your information and may be located wherever SVP Worldwide operates.

#### Protection of Personal Information

SVP Worldwide takes the security of your personal information very seriously. When SVP Worldwide stores your personal data, we use computer systems with limited access housed in facilities using physical security measures.

#### Automated Decision-Making

SVP Worldwide does not make any decisions involving the use of algorithms or profiling that significantly affect you.

#### Integrity and Retention of Personal Information

SVP Worldwide makes it easy for you to keep your personal information accurate, complete, and up to date. We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy. When assessing these periods we carefully examine our need to collect personal information at all and if we establish a relevant need we only retain it for the shortest possible period to realize the purpose of collection unless law requires a longer retention period.

#### Access to Personal Information

We will provide you with access (including a copy) to your personal information for any purpose (including to request that we correct the data if it is inaccurate or delete the data if SVP Worldwide is not required to retain it by law or for legitimate business purposes). We may decline to process requests that jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. To make a request, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@svpworldwide.com?subject=Privacy%20Inquiry%20V052518).

#### Notice for California Residents

California residents who have provided personal information to SVP Worldwide may obtain information regarding SVP’s disclosures, if any, of personal information to third parties for third-party direct marketing purposes.

Requests must be submitted to the following address: SVP Worldwide, 1714 Heil Quaker Blvd, LaVergne, TN 37086. Within 30 days of receiving such a request, we will provide a California Privacy Disclosure, which will include a list of certain categories of personal information disclosed during the preceding calendar year to third parties for their direct marketing purposes, along with the names and addresses of the third parties. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year.

We reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the address specified in this paragraph.

#### Our Company-wide Commitment to Your Privacy

To make sure your personal information is secure, we communicate our privacy and security guidelines to SVP Worldwide employees and strictly enforce privacy safeguards within the company.

#### Privacy Questions

If you have any questions or concerns about SVP Worldwide’s Privacy Policy or data processing, or if you would like to make a complaint about a possible breach of local privacy laws, please [contact us](mailto:privacy@svpworldwide.com?subject=Privacy%20Inquiry%20V052518).

When a privacy question is received we have a dedicated team that triages the contacts and seeks to address the specific concern or query that you are seeking to raise. Where your issue may be more substantive in nature, more information may be sought from you. All such substantive contacts receive a response. If you are unsatisfied with the reply received, you may refer your complaint to the relevant regulator in your jurisdiction. If you ask us, we will endeavor to provide you with information about relevant complaint avenues that may be applicable to your circumstances.

SVP Worldwide may update its Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy.

SVP Worldwide, 1714 Heil Quaker Boulevard, Suite 130, La Vergne, TN 37086

Version SING022119
